partmaster.co.uk 2016-05-31

# Terms & Conditions

## Payment & Security

We want your experience of partmaster to be convenient and secure. We offer a variety of payment options and use industry standard security measures to keep your data and details safe. More details can be found below.

  * View Site Use policy

© DSG Retail Limited and/or Connect Distribution Services Limited

The contents of this website are variously the copyright of DSG Retail Limited, Connect Distribution Services Limited or other copyright owners and are protected by copyright law. All brand names and product names used on this site are registered trade marks or trade names of their respective holders. You may read and print only the material contained on this website solely for personal and non-commercial use.

You agree not to adapt, alter or create any derivative work from any material on this site, or to restrict or inhibit the use or enjoyment of this site by anyone else.

It is not permitted to create any link to or from this web site without prior written consent.

By using this website you agree not to intentionally misuse it. This website may contain hyperlinks to other websites completely unrelated to us; we are not responsible for the content or practices of such websites. Service on this website may be interrupted occasionally and errors may occur. Use of this website is governed by English law and you submit to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts in England.

We try very hard to ensure that all information on this site is accurate. However, just occasionally, an error can occur. If we discover an error in the price or description of a product you have ordered, we will tell you and ask you whether you wish to continue with your order or cancel it.

##### Use of Website Content

You may read and print only the material contained on this website solely for personal and non-commercial use. You are not permitted to publish, store, transmit, show or play in public, change or adapt the content of this website in any way for any purpose whatsoever. Any content found to be being used for commercial use such as images or video will be subject to a minimum charge of £500 per item per month.

You agree not to adapt, alter or create any derivative work from any material on this site, or to restrict or inhibit the use or enjoyment of this site by anyone else. It is not permitted to create any link to or from this website without prior written consent.

  * View Privacy Policy

Any personal information we collect from you will be used in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and other applicable laws. The details we collect will be used:-

    1. to process your order, to maintain guarantee records and to provide after-sales service (we may pass your details to another organisation to supply/deliver products or services you have purchased and/or to provide after-sales service);
    2. to carry out security checks (this may involve passing your details to Experian Limited, or another credit reference agency, who will check details we give them against public and private databases and may keep a record of that check to use in future security checks - this helps to protect you and us from fraudulent transactions); and
    3. to comply with legal requirements

Partmaster is a subsidiary of Dixons Carphone plc and we may need to pass the information we collect to other companies within our group for administrative purposes. We may use third parties to carry out certain activities, such as processing and sorting data, monitoring how customers use our site and issuing our emails for us.

Partmaster would also like to inform you of various promotions, goods and services that may be of interest to you. These would come from any of our chains, including www.partmaster.co.uk, Currys, PC World, Carphone Warehouse and KNOWHOW, or from carefully selected third parties. You may be contacted by post, email, telephone, SMS or such other means as we regard as appropriate, including new technology. If you wish to receive these communications, please tick the "Yes" box when entering your personal details. You may unsubscribe at a later date, if you wish - see "Your rights" section below.

    1. You can ask us to update your personal information by emailing precise details of your request to [contactus@partmaster.co.uk](mailto:contactus@partmaster.co.uk "contactus@partmaster.co.uk"). Please ensure you type "update" in the subject line of your email.
    2. You can ask us not to send you future marketing communications. To do this, simply email [contactus@partmaster.co.uk](mailto:contactus@partmaster.co.uk "contactus@partmaster.co.uk"). Type "No Marketing" in the subject line and then the following in the main text:- 
      * your full name
      * your postal address, including postcode
      * your email address

We will then suppress your data from all direct marketing, although we will still keep it for processing your order and fulfilling customer service and after sale obligations.

Alternatively, you can post your request to the address in (3) below.

    3. You also have the right to request a copy of any personal information we hold about you. To do this, simply write to us at the following address, enclosing a cheque for £10 payable to DSG Retail Limited to cover our administration costs:-

Legal Services  
DSG Retail Ltd  
1 Portal Way  
London  
W3 6RS

  * View Secure Shopping

We recognise the importance of security regarding credit card information you send us over the Internet. We take all the necessary precautions to protect our customers' personal information and to store it securely. You can check that you are shopping in a secure environment by looking for a locked padlock icon (Internet Explorer & Firefox) in the grey bar at the bottom of your screen. This will appear on any page where you are entering personal information (such as your credit card details) – no other page will transmit information about you.

Sensitive information that is transmitted to us online (such as credit card numbers) are encrypted and transmitted to us securely. In addition, access to all of our users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted. Also, the servers on which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment.

At Partmaster we utilise the industry-standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology to encrypt all your personal information including debit or credit card numbers, name and address. The encryption process takes the characters you enter and converts them into bits of code that are then securely transmitted over the Internet.

Other than when we process your original payment or process a refund for you, your credit card details are displayed in a truncated form with only the first 4 digits and the last 4 digits visible. For example your receipt will print a partial credit card number in this way. This means that you will be able to check which card payment was taken against, but in the unlikely event of your parcel being stolen, your full credit card number would not be revealed.

In order to help safeguard unauthorised use of your credit or debit card we check the security code located above the magnetic strip on the back of your card and also the address provided on the order with the address set against the card. This means that you can be rest assured that Partmaster takes all the necessary steps to ensure shopping with us is safe.

Should you wish to speak to us about a previously confirmed order, our staff will never ask you to quote your full credit card.

At the point in the order process where you enter your card details our e-commerce system will request confirmation that the details provided are correct as explained in the sections above.

Most banks now include the Verified by Visa and MasterCard® SecureCode™ virtual 'card present' environment. These are additional security systems which may appear as part of the final stages of the ordering phase.

Should your bank use one of the above systems you will be prompted to enter a password or code in order to proceed. The web page which prompts for this information is provided by your bank where you use a Visa or Mastercard® credit or debit card. The information transmitted from this page is between you and your bank and is in no way used or processed by us. As soon as the card/password is verified you will be returned to our web site to complete your order.

At the point at which this page displays, one of two things will happen. You will be prompted to enrol in the respective cards scheme, where you have not already done so (you will be prompted to create a password or code as part of the enrolment process), alternatively you will be prompted for your password if already enrolled.

Customers can contact or visit their banks website for more information and to enrol independently of this or any other web site.

##### MasterCard®SecureCode™ Explained

MasterCard®SecureCode™ is a simple and secure method of payment at online stores. You will have a private code known only to you and to your bank, your SecureCode™ enhances your existing MasterCard® account by protecting you against unauthorised use of your card when shopping online at participating online retailers.

Every time you pay online at participating retailers, you will be automatically prompted to enter your own private SecureCode™ - just like entering a PIN at a cash machine. In seconds, you gain added protection while shopping online.

For more information regarding MasterCard®SecureCode™ click on the image below

    1. Your IP address (this is your computer's individual identification number) which is automatically logged by our web server. This is used to note your interest in our website.
    2. Your preferences and use of email updates, recorded by emails we send you (if you select to receive email updates on products and offers).

##### Verified by Visa Explained

Verified by Visa is a simple password-protected identity-checking service that takes the risk out of online shopping for both retailers and customers. Retailers are protected against fraudulent transactions and the costs associated with it, while customers can spend with confidence knowing that their payment details are safe.

For more information regarding Verified by Visa click on the image below

  * View Payment Methods

We accept Visa and MasterCard credit cards along with, Visa debit, Visa Electron and Maestro debit cards.

  * View Cookie Policy

What are cookies? And why do we use them?

There are lots of misconceptions about cookies and what they are for. At Partmaster we believe in being open, upfront and honest. In this section we briefly explain the cookie types we use and how they benefit your experience using the website.

Cookies are used by almost all websites. They contain simple pieces of information and they are downloaded on to your pc when you visit the website. Cookies are not programs; they are simple text files that can be used by a website for various purposes. At Partmaster we use cookies to ensure our website works efficiently and also to observe visitor behaviour on our website during a session.

All the information contained in our cookies is used to ensure the website works correctly, delivers the performance you expect and also to improve the overall experience we offer our visitors and customers. Some of the cookies we use are essential to the operation of the website.

### We typically use cookies for the following purposes:

    * To keep track of the items added to the basket 
    * To help identify the order as a whole
    * To view visitor behaviour and areas of the site visited
    * To monitor and run advertising and marketing campaigns

### Overview of the types of cookies used:

**Essential**

Essential cookies are technical cookies that are required for the operation of our site. Without essential cookies our sites can’t operate properly. Typically these cookies are used to support key functions such as the shopping basket and enhanced features like our sign-in accounts.

**Performance**

These cookies allow us to identify and count the number of visitors to our sites and to see how visitors are using the website. This helps us to improve the way our sites work and develop functionality to make shopping with us a more rewarding experience.

**Marketing**

Our site uses a range of cookies for marketing purposes. Marketing cookies record your visits to our sites, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We use this information to make our site and the advertising displayed on them more relevant to your interests. Sometimes we share anonymous information about your browsing activity recorded using cookies with our advertising partners. They may use this information to advertise products that may interest you on other sites. Please note we don’t share any of your personal or sensitive information.

The use of cookies will not result in you receiving unsolicited emails. We understand that not everyone wants to receive marketing information. In order to receive marketing communications from us, you have to opt-in. This can be done during the checkout process or you can [sign up here](http://www.partmaster.co.uk/newsletter-signup.pl). You also have the option to unsubscribe from our email mailing list at anytime.

**Use of cookies & consent**

As described above we, like most other websites, use cookies in the operation of our website. By using this website you are agreeing to the use of cookies for the purposes described. If you do not consent to the use of cookies, please refrain from using this site. You can delete and restrict cookie use in your browser:  

    * View more about Cookie Control

Checking your settings in Internet Explorer 8 and earlier versions

      1. Locate the 'Tools' tab on the menu areas of your browser. Click on this.
      2. There is an option called 'Internet Options' on the list, select this option.
      3. This should open a pop up box with lots of tabbed options. Select the 'Privacy' tab from the list.
      4. Internet Explorer has a high, medium, low auto-adjust system for internet content handling. You can configure your own settings by clicking the advanced tab and ticking the 'Override automatic cookie handling'
      5. Settings above Medium will disable cookies, Medium or below will enable cookies.

Checking your settings in Mozilla Firefox

      1. Locate the 'Tools' tab on the menu areas of your browser. Click on this.
      2. From the list of options on the drop down menu, click on 'Options'
      3. There should be a pop up window appear with tabs along the top. Find the 'Privacy' tab and select this.
      4. You should now have some options for 'Tracking'’ and 'History'. Under the 'History' drop down menu, select 'Use customer settings for history' if you wish to adjust your cookie settings.

Checking your settings in Google Chrome

      1. Look for the spanner icon in Chrome  and click on this
      2. From this menu, select settings…
      3. Within settings you will see tabs on the left hand side. Select the tab called 'Under the Hood'
      4. When this page loads you will see a tab at the top called 'Content Settings' – select this
      5. This brings up your content controls including cookie permissions – select the option you feel most comfortable with

Checking your settings in Safari

      1. Locate the Cog icon at the top of your browser  and click on this.
      2. From the list of options select 'Preferences'
      3. This should open a pop up window with several tabs along the top. From this list select the 'Privacy' option.
      4. This will open the tab page that allows you to control the cookie settings on your browser.

Checking your settings in Opera

      1. Click the Opera file icon in the top left hand corner of your browser.
      2. From the drop down list of options, highlight 'Settings' and then scroll across and select 'Preferences'.
      3. This should open a pop up window with tabs along the top. Choose the 'Advanced' tab.
      4. This shows you the advanced options. On the left hand side there is an option called ‘Cookies’ – click on this option.
      5. This presents the cookie options for your use on this browser.

**If you have another browser …**

Please check the help settings within your browser or use a search engine to find answers on the best way to enable or disable cookies in your chosen browser. Please remember we are not responsible for the content on external websites.

**If you want more information…**

You can visit the following website for an in-depth guide to cookies and how to control, delete and understand them. They even have a great recipe on there for cookies of the edible variety – yum!

<http://www.aboutcookies.org/>

**Data Protection**

We take your privacy seriously and safeguard your data and personal information in compliance with the Data Protection act. For more information on how we use your data please read our [privacy policy](http://www.partmaster.co.uk/payment-security/help.pl).
